Lucas Paglia Grisa, Software Engineering, Full Stack Developer

Telford Ave, Burnaby | lucasgrisa@hotmail.com | +1 (236) 990-1778 | www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-paglia-bb0b33163

Summary

I'm a Software Developer with 5 years of experience. The main technologies that I worked with is Java, Spring Framework, Microservices Architecture and relational (SQL Server, Oragle, PostgreSql and MySQL) and non-relational (Mongo.DB and DynamoDB) databases. During my career I already worked as FullStack with Angula.js and React.js; AWS and Google Cloud tools; CI/CDs; GIT; Docker, Kubernetes and Agile Methodologies.

Experience

Sysmap - 08/2022 to present - Back End Developer:

Outsourced for one of the biggest telecom group from Mexico in Brazil, I worked as Back End Developer. Application using micro services and Spring Framework responsible to validated new phone number until keep the auto manager of user number account.. Also, worked in a continuous delivery following agile methodologies, half Scrum and half Kanban.

- Developed and maintained 50+ functionalities with Spring framework until now;
- Reviewed many pull requests on GitHub.
- Used Postman to access and test REST API;
- Used Postgres database to store data;
- Maintained and monitored pipelines using Jenkins;
- Cloud infrastructure AWS for services and Database:
- Used JIRA to management tasks;
- Participated from different meetings as growmings, plannings, retrospective and tech meetings;
- Mentored new employees. meetings;

ZFlow- 05/2021 to 07/2022 - Back End Developer:

Outsourced for one of the biggest financing companies from Brazil, I worked as Back End Developer. API application responsible to simulate a financing, was the application for the dealer. Also, worked in a continuous delivery following agile methodologies, half Scrum and half Kanban.

- Developed and maintained 250+ functionalities with Spring framework;
- Reviewed many pull requests on GitHub.
- Used Postman to access and test REST API;

- Used MongoDB database to store data;
- Maintained and monitored pipelines using AWS code build;
- Used JIRA to management tasks;
- · Managed containers using Docker;
- Cloud infrastructure AWS for services and Database;
- Participated from different meetings as growmings, plannings, retrospective and tech meetings;
- · Mentored new employees.

QUOD- 05/2020 to 05/2021 – Full Stack Developer:

I worked as Full Stack Software Developer for a Fintech responsible to brazilian PIX. PIX is the Brazilian IP scheme that enables its users — people, companies and governmental entities — to send or receive payment transfers in few seconds at any time. I worked with continuous delivery following agile methodologies, half Scrum and half Kanban.

- Developed and maintained 200+ functionalities, some front end ones with React and another back end ones with Spring framework — micro services architecture.
- Reviewed many pull requests on GitHub.
- Used Postman to access and test REST API;
- Used SQL database to store data;
- Used JIRA to management tasks;
- · Managed containers using Docker;
- Cloud infrastructure AWS for services and Database;
- Participated from different meetings as growmings, plannings, retrospective and tech meetings;
- Mentored new employees.

UOL- 10/2019 to 05/2020 – Full Stack Developer:

I worked as Full Stack Software Developer for the most visited digital producted in Brazil, Universo Online, with Java and JavaScript. The app that I used to work was the Digital Customer Service one in a continuous delivery following agile methodologies, half Scrum and half Kanban.

- Developed and maintained 50+ functionalities, some front end ones with AngularJS and another back end ones with NodeJS and Spring framework Microservices architecture.
- Developed and maintained 50+ Unit Tests.
- Reviewed many pull requests on GitHub.
- Used Postman to access and test REST API;
- Used SQL database to store data;
- Maintained and monitored pipelines using Jenkins CI/CD tool;
- Used JIRA to management tasks;

- Managed containers using Docker and Kubernets;
- Cloud infrastructure AWS for services and Database;
- Participated from different meetings as growmings, plannings, retrospective and tech meetings.

VisualMix- 08/2018 to 11/2019 – Back End Developer:

I worked as Software Developer for an integration application, VB6 and Java based, with continuous delivery. The app goal was to integrate a external with the internal CRM.

- Developed and maintained 200+ functionalities with VB6 and Java;
- Reviewed many pull requests on SVN;
- Developed REST API with Spring framework;
- Used Oracle, Postgres and SQL Server database;
- Responsible many times to share all the achievements and updates to the client.

SuperGeeks- 06/2017 to 08/2018 – Software Programming Instructor:

Professor in Game developer and Computer science in a school for kids.

Education

- Certificate Web Development at Tamwwod College
- MBA Data Science and Analytics at University of São Paulo
- Degree Technology in Digital Games at Technology College of São Paulo

Skills

09/2022 to Present 08/2014 to 12/2020

Back End: Java, Spring Framework, JavaScript, Node.JS **Front End:** HTML, CSS, Angular CLI/JS, React, VUE

Database: PostgreSql, Oracle, MariaDB, MySql, MongoDB, SQL Server

Server: Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GIT, Jenkins, Azure

Languages

Portuguese and English.